Hi friends, today we will see that ICICI
LBD's Q4 earnings have come.  As you
can see in this and this has
come around last night on 15th at around
8:30 PM, so what has happened in ICI LBD which is
an insurance company, see its net profit has
dropped by 2% and it has
now reached around Rs 510 crore and the
gross premium income which mainly their
income comes through premium
of insurance has gone up by 10% and
they have also declared this dividend.  We will
discuss these three points one by one.
So this video can be as short as 5 minutes.
So, watch it patiently
till the end and in this we will discuss
what is coming out of it as per their actual position and
what is their growth potential in the future.
Let's start friends.
So here you can see that
according to the earnings of ICI Lambdfford, its
overall net profit has declined by 2%.   There has been a
drop and it has come down to Rs 510 crore.  And
the fourth quarter earnings as of March 31.
Whereas if compared with last year, then the
earning net profit of Rs 520 crore is as per
last year.
Post Tax Net Net
Profit If we talk about their income, the total
income for the company has risen to Rs
5851 crore in the quarter under the
revenue under the review compared with Rs
5185 crore (165 crore) last year as per Rs
5185, you have seen this rise in revenue.
Gross Direct Premium Income, i.e. the
income that comes through their premiums, which
is their main income, if seen in this, the
company has improved and it has gone up to ₹621
crores.  Against ₹6273 crore
last year growth of the same quarter.
That is, if we look at the growth on a quarter to quarter yearly basis from a year ago, then a
growth of 2.3% has been
seen which is a decent growth.
As far as we said dividend, the final
dividend is also being given on the basis of equity of ₹7 per share
and 70% of the face
value is running at the face value of ₹10, so if
seen on the basis of ₹10, then they are being given dividend on the basis of 70% of the face
value.
They have declared the final dividend and this final dividend has been
declared by ICIS lambd as of March 31, 2025.  So you are going to get a dividend of ₹7
in this stock.   The next
important parameter is the
solvency ratio of any insurance company, if we
look at the previous, it was 2.69 times in the
March ending 2025 and the last one
is 2.62 times as on March 31, 2024, so
according to 2024, our solvency ratio
graph has increased a bit and the
percentage growth in this is the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.5%, which if
seen on solvency ratio year on year basis, then growth has been seen from 2.69%,
so our minimum solvency ratio should be
according to the regulator, according to that
also it is approximately two
times.  If you
look at the price of ICICI LBD now, you will see that it is
running at ₹1823.   The
market cap is ₹90351 crore and it is
trading at a PE of 36.  So,
if we calculate it year-on-year,
according to 2024 and 2025, then year-on-year
growth of 12% is visible in sales.
While profit has declined by approximately 1.2%
EBITDA wise and net
profit has declined by 2%, EBITDA
and EPS have also seen a negative growth of 2%.
Meaning there has been a downfall of 2%
in EBITDA EPS and if we talk about quarter to quarter, if we
talk about quarter to quarter December 2025 and March 2025, then if we
look at it also, a slight decline has been seen.
In December 2025, the
sales were 6161 crores and while in 2025 we will see in 24
and in 2025, the
sales have come as per 6151 crores in March 2025 and
if we talk about EBITDA, it was
962 crores which has now come down to 69 crores, so a
huge decline in EBITDA is being
seen from quarter to quarter
and if we talk about net profit, the
net profit was 727-724 crores which has come down to around
5110 crores by coming to the current net profit.
So, talking about EPS,
it used to be 14.63
in December 2024, which in March financial year 2025,
in Q4, it had
come down to around 10.28.  EPS is also
seeing a decline.  In
this way you can do complete study of Q4 result.
Because I will give its PDF
in my link.  You can do a complete study of this.  According
to which, we have told the overall main
bullet points of this stock
of Asclambd and if you have
any query regarding this, friends,
you can comment, like
and if you have any query, you can ask.
Thank you friends, see you in the next video.
Okay bye-b.